As a child, I was always told to 'eat my greens'.
小时候，我总是被叮嘱“把绿色蔬菜吃掉”。
These were the unappealing vegetables that sat on the edge of my plate.
这些就是放在我盘子边缘那些没有吸引力的蔬菜。
Peas, broccoli and green beans, all looked and tasted disgusting.
豌豆、西兰花和四季豆，看起来和吃起来都很令人厌恶。
Let's face it, when there were so many other edible treats to enjoy, why eat boring veg?
让我们面对现实吧，有那么多其他可以食用的美食，为什么要吃枯燥无味的蔬菜呢？
Since then my taste buds have developed and I'm also fully aware of the health benefits of eating fresh vegetables.
从那以后，我的味蕾逐渐发育成熟，而且我也充分意识到吃新鲜蔬菜对健康的益处。
But we still need reminding of the amazing goodness these green superfoods give us.
但我们仍然需要被提醒这些绿色超级食物带给我们的惊人益处。
In the UK, a campaign based on advice from the World Health Organization has been running for several years to encourage us to eat our '5 A Day' - five portions of fruit and vegetables.
在英国，一项基于世界卫生组织建议的运动已经开展了好几年，鼓励我们做到“每日五蔬果”——即五份水果和蔬菜。
That's because evidence has shown there are significant health benefits to getting at least five 80g portions of a variety of fruit and vegetables every day.
这是因为有证据表明，每天至少摄入五份80克不同种类的水果和蔬菜对健康有显著益处。
But I struggle trying to fit these five portions into my daily diet, partly because I have a sweet tooth and vegetables are, well, tasteless.
但我很难将这五份蔬果纳入我的日常饮食中，部分原因是我喜欢吃甜食，而且蔬菜嘛，确实没什么味道。
Researchers have been looking at how to make eating vegetables more attractive.
研究人员一直在研究如何让吃蔬菜变得更有吸引力。
They analysed the psychology behind our food choices and found that most of us are motivated by taste.
他们分析了我们选择食物背后的心理，发现我们大多数人都是受味道驱使的。
Brad Turnwald from Stanford University says that "studies show that people tend to think of healthier options as less tasty for some reason."
斯坦福大学的布拉德·特恩瓦尔德说：“研究表明，出于某种原因，人们倾向于认为更健康的选择是更寡淡无味的。”
His team carried out an experiment in the university cafeteria where they gave vegetables seductive names and found sales increased by 25 per cent.
他的团队在大学的自助餐厅进行了一项实验，他们给蔬菜起了诱人的名字，结果发现蔬菜的销量增加了25%。
They got rid of healthy labels such as 'wholesome' and gave identical dishes names like 'sizzlin' beans', 'dynamite beets' and 'twisted citrus-glazed carrots'.
他们去掉了像“有益健康的”这样的健康标签，给同样的菜肴起了像“滋滋作响的豆子”、“火爆甜菜”和“扭曲的橙黄釉胡萝卜”这样的名字。
It seems that these indulgent names tempted diners to fill their plates.
似乎这些诱人的名字诱惑用餐者把盘子装满。
Brad Turnwald says that "labels really can influence our sensory experience, affecting how tasty and filling we think food will be."
布拉德·特恩瓦尔德说：“标签确实会影响我们的感官体验，影响我们对食物味道和饱腹感的认知。”
In Europe, a project called VeggieEAT has also been trying to find ways to get people to eat more veg.
在欧洲，一个名为“素食饮食”的项目也一直在试图找到让人们多吃蔬菜的方法。
Project leader, Professor Heather Hartwell believes in "health by stealth", subtly nudging people into eating the right things.
项目负责人希瑟·哈特韦尔教授信奉“偷偷摸摸的健康”，即巧妙地引导人们吃正确的食物。
One idea has been to put a picture of a tasty looking fruit on a supermarket trolley as a hint about buying something from the fruit aisle.
其中一个想法是在超市的手推车上放一张看起来很美味的水果图片，作为从水果区购买东西的暗示。
She says, "Choice is a really complex thing.
她说：“选择是一件非常复杂的事情。
But this study suggests that giving vegetables an indulgent tag can help raise their hierarchy."
但这项研究表明，给蔬菜贴上诱人的标签可以帮助提高它们的等级。”
Certainly, eating 'twisted citrus-glazed carrots' does sound tempting, even if it just tastes like a carrot, but if it makes us eat more vegetables then that can only be a good thing for our health.
当然，吃“扭曲的橙黄釉胡萝卜”听起来确实很诱人，即使它吃起来就像普通胡萝卜一样，但如果这能让我们多吃蔬菜，那对我们的健康肯定是件好事。